[bright music]
Bestfriend,
just the other day, you were on cloud nine.
But now, it seems like you're mourning.
Try to understand him too.
He had his own life
before the two of you met.
You can't suddenly
become everything in his life.
Same with you.
Didn't it take you
quite a while to get over
that long-distance relationship of yours?
The point is, he lied to me.
He said he would donate
those clothes to a charity.
That's why I was so clueless
when I spoke to his ex in the store.
But you're just like him! You also lied to
your mom when you lost her money, remember?
Because you love her.
You didn't want her
to feel hurt or anxious.
It's just the same with K-pop!
He doesn't want you to
feel hurt or worried because...
I'm not sure about that, bestfriend.
Maybe it's better to avoid him for now.
How will you do that?
You live under the same roof.
You eat from the same plate that he uses.
You drink from the same glass he does.
- You poop in the same - - Eew!
I get it.
Why do you need to avoid him, anyway?
Shouldn't you be there to support him?
Moving on from a past
relationship is not that easy.
Think about it, you were in a long-distance
relationship for six months only.
But after the breakup,
you almost committed...
Forget it. Let's not
talk about it, anymore.
That's exactly my point!
It's not easy to move on from someone
you've been with for that many years.
What if he still cares about him?
What if he still loves him?
What if I'm just a rebound?
Finally! That's the reason behind it all!
Why are you even comparing
yourself to K-pop's ex?
That's not love! That's pride!
Fine, but there's a big possibility
that he still feels something for him.
Maybe he's just using
me to get back at him.
He already returned the clothes, right?
So it means you're not a rebound!
[soft music]
Why does he get mad
each time I call him Josh?
Simple! He remembers his
ex every time you call him Josh.
He wants to move on!
What are you going to do now, bestfriend?
How will you avoid him?
Where will you stay?
I don't know.
I'm thinking about taking
a few days off from work.
I told you to take things slowly.
You love deeply, yet
you're also very insecure.
Why not come home instead?
There’s no longer a
reason for you to stay there.
You probably won't find that
disgusting scammer anymore.
[soft music]
Hi, Mom, how are you?
I'm doing okay, son. How about you?
I'm okay, too.
Looks like you're headed somewhere?
I'm stepping outside for
a bit to get some fresh air.
Alright, this won’t take up much time.
Your Aunt Susan called.
She needs to borrow money because your
cousin Junjun is still in the hospital.
I'm thinking of lending them some
because I feel bad for their situation.
Your cousin has been in the
hospital for quite a while now.
Their hospital bill is piling up.
Okay, Mom.
How much are we planning to send them?
They're asking for 40,000 pesos.
But I told them that we
don't have that kind of money.
Maybe we can send them half?
Okay, Mom, I'll send them
twenty thousand pesos.
But are you sure you'll have
enough money left for yourself?
Yes, Mom, don't worry.
Just send me the full name,
address, and contact number.
Okay, I’ll send it to you.
Thank you so much,
son. You're truly reliable.
Okay, I won't hold you up any further.
I’ll call you again, okay?
Love you, son. Thank you.
Love you too, Mom. Take care.
Where have you been?
I've been calling you. You
haven’t been picking up.
Oh, uh,
I was just with my girl friend.
Or not my “girlfriend” girl friend.
Just uh,
a friend who happens to be a girl.
What's her name?
Her name? Uh…
Mitch… Mitchie...
Friend of mine from high school.
Where was she coming in from?
Well, uh... from San... Francisco.
San Francisco!
How did she get into LA?
Well, she... she drove.
Wow.
You must be very special to her.
What? Why?
To make time for you like that.
San Francisco to LA is
like a six, seven hour-drive.
She must’ve been real tired.
Yeah, yeah... She was.
But she was only here for one night.
And I have to leave soon so
it just made sense.
Oh,
I got this for you, by the way.
Thank you. Am I still
picking you up tonight.
Oh, no need, uh...
Michelle, or Mitchie,
she’s going to pick me up tonight.
Didn’t you just see each other?
Yeah, but you know, it was super brief.
Because like you mentioned,
um, 6 1/2, 7-hour long drive...
That’s just… She was really tired.
Right. I thought she was
just staying for one night?
Yeah, yeah, um...
yeah, we're...
well, yeah, but...
I mean it was such a long drive…
That we didn’t meet for a long time.
So we just...
we just thought we’re gonna do it again.
Okay.
Do you want me to come pick you up
and bring you to wherever it is you're
going after your meeting with your
“friend”?
No need. She's...
She’s got it.
[soft music]
All right,
I’ll see you at ten.
Wait, no, no,
but she’s gonna be the
one who actually drives me.
Yeah, I have to come
back and lock up the store.
Oh yeah, yeah. Right, right.
Okay.
[soft music]
Oh, shoot. You’re still here.
Hello?
Where did you go?
[bright music]
So,
you're the one that my brother's
doing all this cooking for?
I have to say I’m pretty jealous.
My brother would never do that for me.
How did you get inside?
I might know where my little
brother puts his spare keys.
[bright music]
Do you…
do you smell that?
What?
I don’t know. Something...
bad, just...
really stinky.
I don’t know where
it’s coming from though.
Yeah, I don’t know but, um,
I’m gonna go take a quick
shower. I'll be right back.
Nice meeting you.
Awww...
My little brother is so inspired.
[bright music]
Now I know why.
Don't worry about me.
My brother's happiness is everything.
Does he know you're here?
No.
- Oh, did you want me to call him?
- Please don't.
But I thought you're here to visit him?
Yeah, I am.
Of course, I want to see him.
The question is,
does he even want to see me?
What?
He didn't even tell you about me yet?
My brother ran away from home.
Four years ago.
Why?
Our father, he’s...
very very strict.
Um,
and my brother being the only son,
all the expectations were put on him.
And with him being gay, I mean,
our whole family knew,
even my dad,
except he’s in complete denial.
So even though it was this open secret,
my brother still had
to come out officially,
so that he could live his
life how he wanted to and
be with people he wanted to be.
My dad
did not want to accept that and
he tried to send my
brother to the military.
I think he thought that it would
transform Joshua into
his idea of a real man.
As if Joshua doing a thousand sit-ups
here and a thousand push-ups there
would make him just get up and
announce to everyone “I’m a real man now.”
I mean, obviously Joshua
wasn’t go through with it.
[soft music]
But, um,
it pushed him to ran away and
just leave all of that behind.
I did stay in touch with him
though, at least in the beginning.
I...
I never got to see him but we
were e-mailing pretty regularly.
I knew where he was
staying, where he was working,
all of his schedules and things like that.
Um, yeah...
It’s been about a year
since we’ve spoken though.
Why did he just stop talking to you?
[soft music]
I broke a promise that I made with him.
What promise was that?
That I would never tell our parents
that we were in communication.
Why did you do that?
I didn’t really have a choice.
When Joshua broke up with his
boyfriend, I had to tell our mom.
Has he ever told you about him?
Ivan?
Yeah.
When Ivan first moved to the US,
my brother was the one who
was helping him with everything
in helping him get settled in here.
He was just so in love with him,
absolutely head over heels.
I think it was the first time in so many
years that my brother
felt like somebody truly
loved him and embraced him for who he was,
no questions asked.
And they were really happy together.
But then everything
changed when Ivan got a job.
You know, he got his papers,
started working at this hospital, and...
he met this doctor
there, a super-rich doctor.
I don’t know.
And they had this secret
affair for more than a year.
When Joshua found out,
it just broke him.
He couldn’t deal with it, you know, so
he broke up with Ivan and
moved out of their apartment. But...
he had nowhere to go.
I mean, he had no one else.
He literally had nothing.
I don’t think he could even afford
to buy an airbed or anything. And I -
I was just afraid that he would starve
or I’ll get a call that he was
dead on the street somewhere.
I... I didn’t know what else to do, so
I had to break our
promise and I told my mom.
So she gave me some
money to send to Joshua.
[soft music]
He didn’t accept the money, though.
He thought it was from our father.
He said
he'd rather die
than to ask for help from somebody
who couldn’t accept him for who he was.
He sent back all the money and…
I haven’t been able to
reach him ever since.
How did you even know where he
lives now? How did you find him?
Okay, please don't tell him.
And I’m not proud of what I did but
I might have figured
out his e-mail password.
It's his birthday, if you
can even believe that!
He has this big ego and
pride and whatnot but
his email password is just his birthday!
I just couldn’t keep watching my mom
wither away being so
worried sick about him and…
[soft music]
our dad too.
He’ll never admit that but…
he asks about Joshua almost everyday.
But now I am just...
I'm so relieved.
My brother is cooking for someone again.
I just want you to be happy and maybe
Joshua will call me one day and say
guess what I cooked for, um...
what… what is your name?
Andre?
Are you asking me?
It’s Andre.
Andre.
Just, um...
try to be patient with my little brother.
He can be very sensitive,
Given everything he's been through.
[soft music]
- Here's your change. Have a good day.
- Thanks. You too.
You're early. Did you have
a good time with your friend?
Okay, get off. What if a customer sees?
I don't care.
You slept with your friend, didn't you?
What?
No!
Just be honest.
I won’t be pissed if your honest.
I didn't sleep with anyone.
Then why are you being so sweet?
Am I not allowed to be sweet?
I hate men.
You just cheat
and then act extra sweet to cover it up.
Joshua, I didn’t cheat on you.
After spending the whole
night with your friend?
Come on!
My friend Michelle.
What if it it’s not Michelle?
What if it's a Michael?
Okay, there's no Michelle,
there’s no Michael,
there's no cheating, that’s for sure.
I lied.
But I only did it because...
I was jealous.
Why would you be jealous?
I’m sorry. I didn't tell you sooner.
[dramatic music]
I... I just
I didn’t want you to think that I -
It’s okay.
It doesn’t even matter.
[dramatic music]